# **Derelle Kirksey**

derelle.p.kirksey@gmail.com - (404) 953-9320 - San Diego, CA 92108

LinkedIn URL: https://www.linkedin.com/in/Derelle-Kirksey

Portfolio: https://citizenSNPs.github.io

#### **Profile**

Data analyst and engineering professional with experience at multiple large fast-paced public companies. Polished written and presentation skills and business savvy in interpreting and applying data. In-depth knowledge of relational databases, analytics, and business intelligence.

### **Experience**

## Amazon – San Diego, CA

Data Analyst II / Business Intelligence Analyst II

09/2022 - 03/2023

- Creates product and customer insights from customer survey data via Excel/SQL/Python/Amazon Quicksight/Redshift
- Translates Customer Experience survey findings (e.g. NPS, CSAT) and other sources of feedback (e.g. customer comments)
  across different touch points into actionable insights and influence decision making and business optimizations
- Represents the voice of customers by sharing insights and collaborating with appropriate business partners to drive improvements and customer-centric decisions
- Designs and builds insight-driven tools, reports, and dashboards that provide real-time and easy access to customer feedback across the organization

## Johnson & Johnson/Janssen R&D - San Diego, CA

Clinical Data Analyst II

01/2022 - 09/2022

- Performed multivariate analysis of biomarker data in connection with neuroscience clinical trials for developing biomarker-based patient subgroups
- Implemented statistical techniques and created data models to validate data interpretations and to improve predictions of clinical trial results
- Created analytical tools in Python to generate and validate hypotheses and to support statistical/clinical teams in finding new leads

## Illumina - San Diego, CA

Engineer I – Development

08/2019 - 06/2021

- Managed onboarding and validation tasks for existing lab equipment and test operations for new and existing lab management protocols
- Developed Hamilton and Tecan liquid handling scripts for product software systems and high-volume manufacturing use
- Led the design, development, and procurement effort for a replacement Laboratory Information Management System (LIMS) via AWS Lambda and Illumina's InterOp sequencing library, and single-handedly maintained frontend (AngularJS), DevOps (Rancher), and backend/database (MySQL) operations for Illumina's CORE LIMS system, SAGE/Rex

Clinical Laboratory Technician II / Data Analyst

06/2016 - 08/2019

- Customized SQL queries and created new data analytical tools using Python, R, Microsoft SQL Server, and Tableau
- Successfully led an interdepartmental team in the validation of Illumina LIMS software
- Proactively developed automated processing scripts in Python to review QC data, built to replace previous manual spot-check process
- Underwent Intermediate/Advanced Tableau training for data visualization and dashboard creation

#### Education

B.S., Neuroscience & Behavioral Biology

2010 - 2015

Emory University - Atlanta, GA

### Certifications

- Hamilton MICROLAB VENUS Software Training I #VST119.11
- Tecan EvoWare Liquid Handling Standard Software Training I

#### **Publications**

Datta, R., & Kirksey, D. (2022). Preservation of myelin in patients with relapsing multiple sclerosis treated with ponesimod compared to teriflunomide. Multiple Sclerosis Journal, 632.